The news never ends.
This is tenneti GCR,
you get all the news
you need, all day long.
Good morning. It's 42° and
10:30 on this Thursday October 15.
I'm Standale Brodston.
Here's what's happening.
It's day eighteen of
the garbage stall,
with 10,000 tons of garbage
piling up every day,
even the nicest sections of the
city are looking like swamps.
Health commissioner Edward O'Roark is
declaring a citywide state of emergency
for the first time in decades.
There's no need to wait until somebody
dies or comes down with typhoid fever.
It's already a serious situation.
It's something that affects
almost everyone in the city,
no matter who they are
or where they live.
You can't go down no one avenue without
seeing nothing but garbage and rats.
It's starting to affect my business when customers
can't get in here because of garbage situation.
When out there, not just smell it,
but I think to look at it,
its terrible.
It don't affect me, except for the
the very bad smell, it's horrific.
The mess.
I've been in this country for 50 years
and I've never seen anything like it.
What is this world coming to?
Put them in the room there and
sit there and talk 'till they got it over with.
24 hours, 48 hours,
how long it takes.
The Idea of the National Guard pulling
in and cleaning up, it's good idea!
In other news the Building
Industry of Landlords today
expressed concern over the latest
increase in heating oil prices.
Rangers in the Metro area are
searched to fill them in...
Let's get it.
- Yo, what's up with your shoes, bro?
- Nice outfit, huh?
If you're gonna be a clown, at least you
can be a bill-boy, you know that, right?
- Hey!
- Stop it!
- Go! Go! Go!
- Hey!
- Come on, Kyle, let's go!
- We've got the sign!
Let's go!
- Stop there!
- Come on!
Watch your go!
Make me stop, clown.
Hey!
C'mon clown, you are not
catching up.
Stop them!
Come on!
- Come on!
- Get out of the way!
Stop them!
Hey!
You bastards.
Come on, beat his ass up.
Come on, this guy's weak,
can't do nothing.
Harder! Harder!
Beat him up.
Take his stuff.
- Let's go, let's go!
- Come on, come on, come on!
- Let's go, let's go, let's go!
Is it just me,
or is it getting crazier out there?
It is certainly tense.
People are upset.
They're struggling.
Looking for work.
These are tough times.
How 'bout you?
Have you been keeping
up with your journal?
Yes, Ma'am.
Great.
Did you bring it with you?
Arthur...
last time I asked you to
bring your journal with you
for these appointments.
Can I see it?
I've been using it as a--
as a journal,
but also as a joke diary.
Funny thoughts or
observations.
I think I told you I'm pursuing
a career in stand-up comedy.
No, you didn't.
I think I did.
"I just hope my death makes
more cents than my life."
How does it feel to
have to come here?
Does it help
to have someone to talk to?
I think I felt better when
I was locked up in a hospital.
And having thought more about
why you were locked up?
Who knows?
I was wondering if you could ask the
doctor to increase my medication?
Arthur, you're on seven
different medications.
Surely, they must
be doing something.
I just don't want to
feel so bad anymore.
Can you please stop
bothering my kid?
- Sit!
- I wasn't bothering him...
- Just stop!
- I was...
What, you think that's funny?
I'm sorry, I have a co...
"It's a medical condition causing sudden, frequent and
uncontrollable laughter that doesn’t match
how you feel. It can happen in people with a brain
injury or certain neurological conditions."
I'm sorry.
Happy? Did you check the mail
before you came up?
Yeah, mom.
Nothing.
And finally tonight, just when you thought
it couldn't get any worse.
Authorities are saying the city is
under siege by scores of rats.
- And not just any rats - super rats.
- More hard to kill.
He must not be
getting any of my letters.
It's Thomas Wayne, mom.
- He is a busy man.
- Oh, please.
I worked for that
family for years.
The least he could do
is write back.
Here, all worked up.
Eat.
- You need to eat.
How skinny you are.
He will make a great mayor.
Everybody says so.
Oh, yeah?
Everybody who?
- Who do you talk to?
- Well, everybody on the news.
He is the only one who
could save the city.
He owes it to us.
Come, sit. It's starting.
Oh, my!
From NCB studios
in Gotham city!
It's Live with Murray Franklin!
Tonight Murray welcomes,
Sandra Winger,
comedian Skip Byron and the
piano styling of Yeldon & Chantel!
Joining Murray as always,
Ellis Drane and
his Jazz Orchestra.
And now, without further ado,
Murray Franklin!
Thank you.
We've got a great
looking audience today.
- Yeah!
- Murray!
Wow.
Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you.
So, everybody's heard about the super
rats stutter in Gotham now, right?
Well, today, the mayor said
he has a solution.
You ready for this?
Super cats.
- But no, serious it is, I mean these guys are...
- I love you, Murray!
I love you, too.
Hey, Bobby, will you
put the lights on?
Who is that?
Was that you?
You wanna stand up, please?
Stand. Stand up for me.
There.
What's your name?
Hi, Murray.
Arthur.
- Arthur?
- My name is Arthur.
Ah, okay, well, there is something
special about you, Arthur. I could tell.
- Where are you from?
- I live right here in the city.
With my m--mother.
Okay, hold on. Hold on.
There is nothing funny about that.
I lived with my mother
before I made it. Just me and her.
I'm that kid who's father went
out for a pack of cigarettes.
And he never came back.
I know what that's like, Murray.
I've been the man of the house
for as long as I can remember.
I take good care of my mother.
All that sacrifice,
she must love you very much.
She does.
She always tells me to smile
and put on a happy face.
She says I was put here to
spread joy and laughter.
Wow!
I like that. I like that a lot!
Come on down.
Come on! For that,
you've got to come down.
Come on!
Okay, we've got
a big show tonight.
Stay tuned.
We will be right back.
That was great, Arthur.
Thank you.
I mean, I loved hearing
what you had to say, it made my day.
Thanks, Murray.
You see all this, the lights, the show,
the audience, all that stuff?
I'd give it all up in a heartbeat
to have a kid like you.
You're such a jerk.
- What's up, ladies?
- Hey, Randall. What's up?
Another day in chuckle town.
You okay?
I heard about the
beat-down you took.
Fucking savages.
It was just a bunch of kids.
I should've left them alone.
No, they'll take everything
from here if you do that.
All the crazy shit out there?
They're animals.
You know what?
Here.
What is it?
Take it.
It's for you.
You gotta protect yourself out there,
otherwise you're
gonna get fucked.
Randall.
I'm not supposed to have a gun.
Don't sweat it, Art.
No one has to know.
And you can pay me
back some other time.
You know you're my boy.
Arthur... Hoyt wants to
see you in his office.
Hey, Gary, you know what
I've always wondered?
No idea.
Do you people call it miniature golf,
or is it just golf to you?
Punch him in the dick, Gary.
Hello, Hoyt.
Gary said you wanted to see me?
How's the comedy career?
You're a famous stand-up yet?
Not quite.
Just been working on
my material.
No, don't sit.
This will be quick.
Look.
I like you, Arthur.
You know, lot of the guys here
think you're a freak, but I like you.
I don't even know
why I like you.
But I got another complaint.
And it's starting to piss me off.
Kenny's Music.
The guy said you disappeared.
Never even returned his sign.
Because I got jumped.
Didn't you hear?
For a sign?
It's bullshit.
It doesn't make sense,
just give him his sign back.
He's going out of business
for God's sake, Arthur.
Why would
I keep that sign?
How the fuck do I know?
Why does anybody do anything?
If you don't return the sign,
I got to take it out
of your pay check.
Are we clear?
Listen, I'm trying to help you. Okay?
Now I tell you something else.
The other guys, they don't feel
comfortable around you, Arthur.
Because people think
you're weird, okay?
And I can't have that around me.
I want it-- I want it to work out---
Wait, wait, wait!
Wait!
Thank you.
This building is
so awful, isn't it?
This building is so awful,
right, mommy?
Yeah, sweetie.
I hear you, GiGi.
It's so awful, mommy.
Right, mommy?
- It's fine.
- This building's so awful, isn't it?
Hey.
Come on.
Head up.
Maybe the mailman
is throwing them away.
Mom, why are these letters
so important to you?
- What do you think he's gonna do?
- He's gonna help us.
You worked
for them, what?
30 years ago?
Why would he help us?
Because Thomas
Wayne is a good man.
If he knew how we were living,
if he saw this place,
it would make him sick.
I can't explain it to
you any better than that.
I don't want you
worrying about money.
Or me.
Everybody’s telling me that my
stand-up is ready for the big clubs.
But, Happy, what makes you
think you could do that?
- What do you mean?
- I mean...
don't you have to be funny
to be a comedian?
Hey, what's your name?
Arthur.
Hey, Arthur.
You're a really good dancer.
I know.
And who is not?
Him.
Happy! What was that?
Are you okay?
Mom, what?
That noise!
Did you hear that noise?
I'm-- I'm watching
an old war movie!
Turn it down!
It's hard, mom.
It's nice to see these
couples are at my show.
I have a wife,
we love to role play.
Yes. Yes, very sexy.
My favorite one right now is...
professor and senior who really
needs to pass my class to graduate.
Yes.
So I tell you how I operate.
I'm a professor at a prestigious
New England university.
And my wife is a senior in
my intro to western civ.
I know, I know, why is she--
why is she a senior in intro?
I didn't buy it either.
So she comes to me
during my office hours,
Monday and Wednesday
3:00 to 5:00,
and she says, - excuse me,
professor Lewis.
I can't use my real last name at this
collage 'cause they don't hire Jews.
Something I'll address once
I have a tenure, but for now.
She says, - excuse me professor Lewis.
I think I might be in danger
of failing intro to western civ.
and I just want you to know I'm
willing to do anything to pass.
I said "anything?",
and she says "Aah".
Oh. Hey.
Hey.
Were you following me today?
Yeah.
I thought that was you.
I was hoping you'd come
in and rob the place.
I have a gun.
I'll come by tomorrow.
You're so funny, Arthur.
Yeah...
You know, I--I do
stand-up comedy.
You should maybe come
and see a show sometime.
I could do that.
Yeah?
Yeah.
You let me know when?
♪ If you're happy and you know it,
wiggle your ears ♪
♪ If you're happy and you know it, ♪
♪  and you feel it, well, just show it ♪
♪ If you're happy and you know it, ♪
♪ wiggle your ears ♪
♪ stomp your feet ♪
♪ If you're happy and you know it, ♪
♪ and you feel it, well, just show it ♪
♪ If you're happy and you know it,
stomp your feet ♪
♪ If you're happy and you know it, ♪
♪ shout "Hooray" ♪
♪ and you feel it,--- ♪
Hoyt, please.
I love this job.
Arthur, I need to know why you
brought a gun into a kids hospital.
It's a part.
It's part of my act now.
That's bullshit!
Bullshit!
What kind of a clown
carries a fucking gun?
Besides, Randall told me you tried
to buy a .38 off him last week.
- Randall told you that?
- You 're fuck up, Arthur.
And a liar.
You're fired!
I'm telling you, she wanted my number.
We should have just stayed.
You're dreaming, man.
She wasn't interested... at all.
Are you nuts? Did you see
how close we were dancing!?
She was in love, bro.
She couldn't wait
to get away from you.
Ryan. Ryan, am I crazy?
Tell him what you saw.
Hey. You want
some french fries?
Hello....?
- I'm talking to you. Hey.
- No, thank you.
You sure?
They're really good.
Don't ignore him.
He's being nice to you.
Is something funny, asshole?
Bitch!
♪ Isn't it rich? ♪
♪ Are we a pair? ♪
♪ Me here, at last on the ground ♪
♪ You in mid-air ♪
♪ Send in the clowns. ♪
♪ Isn't it bliss? ♪
♪ Don't you approve? ♪
Please. Don't.
♪ One who keeps tearing around, ♪
♪ One who can't move. ♪
♪ Where are the clowns? ♪
♪ There ought to be clowns. ♪
So, buddy, tell us.
What's so fucking funny?
Nothing. I---
I have a---
I have a condition.
I'll tell you what you have,
asshole.
We've got a kicker, huh? Hey,
hold him steady, hold him steady.
Stay down, freak!
No! No!
Hey! Help! Help!
Hey!
Stay clear of the closing doors.
I read it was a guy
in a full make-up.
No, it says right here
it was a mask.
Either way, I think
it's good for business.
They got clowns in front
of every newspaper.
- Big man, what's the good word?
- Hey.
Hey, Arthur.
I heard what happened.
Sorry, mate.
Yeah, it doesn't seem fair,
you get fired like that.
Did you really bring a gun to
the children's hospital, Arty?
What the fuck would
you do that for?
Is that part of
your new act, Arthur?
If your dancing doesn't do the trick,
you just gonna shoot yourself?
Why don't you ask
Randall about it?
It was his gun.
- What?
- I still owe you for that, don't I?
What the fuck are
you talking about?
Stop talking outta
your ass, Art!
Oh, no!
I forgot to punch out.
And as our city tries
to make sense of the brutal
triple murder on the subway last week.
We're joined by Thomas Wayne.
- Happy, look. Thomas Wayne's on TV.
- He has a personnel connection
- Yes, mother.
- this tragedy.
Thanks for having me on show.
They're asking him about
those horrible subway murders.
Thank you, Thomas. I know
this is a difficult time for you.
- Why him?
- These young men all were...
Looks like his compaign.
Yes, all three of them
worked for Wayne investments.
Good, decent, educated,
although, I didn't know
any of them personally.
Like all the Wayne employees,
past and present, they were family.
You hear that! I told you.
We're family.
There now seems to be a a groundswell
of anti-rich sentiment in the city.
It's almost as if our less fortunate
residents are taken the side of the killer.
Yes and it's a shame.
It's one of the reasons why
I'm considering a run for mayor.
Gotham has lost its way.
What about the eyewitness report of
the suspect being a man in a clown mask?
Well, it makes total sense to me.
What kind of a coward would do
something that cold-blooded ?
Someone who hides
behind a mask.
Someone who is envious of those
more fortunate than themselves,
yet they're too scared
to show their own face.
And until all those kind of
people change for the better..
those of us who've made
something of our lives,
will always look at
those who haven't
as nothing but clowns.
Thomas Wayne, thank you
for coming in this morning.
It's not funny.
I heard this song on the
radio the other day.
And the guy was singing,
that his name was Carnival.
- Arthur.
- It's just crazy,
because that's my
clown name. At work.
But until a while ago
it was like nobody
ever saw me.
Even I didn't know
if I really existed.
Arthur, I have some
bad news for you.
You don't listen, do you?
I don't think you ever
really hear me.
You just ask the same
questions every week:
"How was your job?"
"Are you having any
negative thoughts?"
All I have are negative thoughts.
But you don't listen. Anyway,
I said,
for my whole life
I didn't know if I
even really existed.
But I do.
And people are
starting to notice.
They've cut our funding.
We're closing down
our offices next week.
The city's cut funding across the board,
social services is part of that.
This is the last time
we will be meeting.
Okay.
They don't give a shit about
people like you, Arthur.
And they really don't give a shit
about people like me, either.
Oh, fuck.
How am I supposed to
get my medication now?
Who do I talk to?
I'm sorry, Arthur.
I think, uh-- I think most women
look at sex like buying a car.
You know, like, "can I see
myself in this long term?"
Is it safe. Is it reliable?
Could it kill me?
Most guys look at sex like parking a car.
We're like "there's a spot".
"There is another spot,
that would work."
"Oh, I have to pay?
Never mind."
"Handicapped?
Hope no one sees us."
Alright that's my time.
Thank you very much, guys.
One more time, ya' all.
Alright, this next comic describes
himself as a lifelong Gotham resident
who from a young age
was always told that:
"his purpose in life was to bring laughter
and joy into this cold, dark world."
Umm.. okay.
Please help me welcome
Arthur Fleck, ya' all. Arthur Fleck.
Hello, it's good to be here---
I hate--
I---I hated
school as a kid.
I hated school as a--
as a kid.
But my mother
would always say, -
"you should enjoy it.
One day you'll have to work for a living."
"No I won't, Ma.
I'm gonna be a comedian!"
Here is one.
You know, I was just
thinking the other day,
why are the rich people so---
Do you believe that shit?
Fuck 'em!
I think the guy that
did it is a hero.
Three less pricks in Gotham city,
only a million more to go.
I know what you're gonna be thinking.
And buddy, as always
thanks for the laughs.
Sure, will see you again.
You will be here, right? I hope.
Tomorrow night,
we have Diana Hudson,
Grieg Gordon, and animal
expert Hugh Little.
Thanks for watching.
Good night. And always remember
"That's Life".
That's life.
Mom, time to wake up.
We go to bed.
No, Happy.
I wrote him a new letter.
Come on, dance with me.
For Thomas Wayne.
That's important.
You smell like cologne.
Because I just had a big date.
Just don't forget to mail it.
You're gonna kill me!
You're gonna give me a hard time!
- I won't give you a---
- No! No!
I'm not talking to you until
you stop being angry!
Okay.
I'm not angry, mom.
I'm not angry.
Please.
Mom, is this real?
He is an extraordinary man, Happy.
He is a very powerful man.
We were in love.
He said it was best if we would not be
together because of appearances.
And I couldn’t tell
anyone because,
well,
I signed some papers.
And besides, you can imagine
what people would say about
Thomas and me and...
what they’d say about you.
What would they say, mom?
Hi.
What's your name?
I'm Bruce.
Bruce.
I'm Arthur.
That's better.
Bruce! Bruce!
- Get away from that man.
- It's okay. I'm a good guy.
What are you doing?
Who are you?
I'm here to see Mr. Wayne.
Well, you shouldn't be
speaking to his son.
- Where did you get him these flowers?
- No, they're not real.
It's...magic.
- I was just trying to make him smile.
- Well, It's not funny, is it?
Do I need to call the police?
No, please.
My mother's name is Penny.
Penny Fleck.
She used to work here years ago.
Can you please tell Mr. Wayne
I need to see him?
You're her son?
Yeah.
Did you know her?
I know about the two of them.
She told me everything.
There's nothing to know.
There is no "them".
Your mother was delusional.
- She was a sick woman.
- Don't
say that.
Just go.
Before you make
a fool of yourself.
- Thomas Wayne is my farther.
He left me!
Let go!
Keep your respiration’s around 15.
Slow, there're some stairs
coming up.
Mom?
- What happened?
- Who are you?
- I'm her son.
- Oh, great.
- What happened?
- You can probably help us out to decide.
- We don't know what happened yet.
- Hop in the back of the ambulance.
Come on. We have
one more left.
I'm getting a little resistence
here. Come on, give her a lift.
Position her head.
Lift.
Excuse me, sir.
- Does your mother take any medications?
- No.
- Excuse me, I can't hear you.
- Sir, what was the last time
you spoke to her? - I don't know.
Mr. Fleck.
Sorry to bother you.
I'm detective Garrity.
This is my partner
detective Burke.
We had a few questions for you,
but you weren’t home.
So... we spoke with
your mother.
Oh.
What did you say to her?
- Did you do this?
- What?
No.
No, no. No, we just
asked her some questions.
And she got hysterical..
hyperventilating,
then collapsed and hit her
head pretty hard.
Yeah, the doctor said
she had a stroke.
We're sorry to hear about that.
But like I said, I still has
some questions for you.
They're about the subway killings
that happened last week.
- You've heard about them, right?
- Yeah.
- It's horrible.
- Right.
So with spoke with your
boss over at...Ha-Ha's.
He said you were fired for bringing
a gun into the children's hospital.
- Is that true, Mr. Fleck?
- It was a prop.
It was part of my act.
I'm a party clown.
Alright, so why were you fired?
They said I wasn't funny enough.
Can you imagine that?
If you don't mind,
I have to go and take
care of my mother.
Your boss also gave us
one of your cards.
This condition of yours, laughing.
Is it real, or some
sort of a clown thing?
- "A clown thing?"
- Yeah.
I mean, part of your act?
What do you think?
It's exit only.
She's gonna be okay.
I'll get a coffee.
- You want one?
- Yeah.
So, the other night I told
my youngest son, Billy,
you know, the new one, the--
not so bright one,
I-- I told him the garbage
strike is still going on, Billy,..
and he says, and
I'm not kidding, Billy says,
"So where are we gonna
get all our garbage from?".
And finally,
in a world where everyone
thinks they could do my job,
we got this video tape from Pogo's
comedy club right here in Gotham.
Here's a guy who thinks if you just keep
laughing, it'll somehow make you funny.
Check out this joker.
Oh, no!
I hated school as a kid.
But my mother would always say,
"You know, you should enjoy it.
One day you'll have to work for a living."
"No I won't, Ma.
I'm gonna be a comedian!"
You should have
listened to your mother.
And one more.
One more, Bobby.
Uh...let's see one more.
I love this guy.
It's funny.
When I was a little boy
and told people I was
gonna be a comedian,
everyone laughed at me.
Well, no one's laughing now.
You can say that again, pal.
Alright,
- We've got a great show for you tonight.
- Sure.
--here actress Joan Mulligan,
and new music from
Melruban and the stiff.
As tensions mount
around the metro area
mayor Stokes has pleaded for
cooler heads to prevail.
City services has
been affected
and some businesses have decided
to remain closed amid the unrest.
Chuck Stevens filed this report.
The anger and resentment that's
been building in the city for weeks
seem close to exploding.
Protesters, many dressed as
clowns, took the streets today
in one of the several demonstrations
taking on the city's elite,
including a massive rally
outside the Wayne home.
What's the point of all this?
Fuck the rich!
Fuck Mr. Wayne.
That's what this all fucking thing was
about.
Fuck all this system!
Wayne, who recently announced his running
for mayor will be attending the benefit.
You might remember, it was
Thomas Wayne who first referred to
many of Gotam's
residents as "clowns".
Today, he offered little
in way of an apology.
Well, what I will say is, there's
something wrong with those people.
And I'm here to help them.
I'm gonna lift them out of poverty,
help make they're lives better.
That's why I'm running.
They may not realize it,
but I'm their only hope.
Down with Wayne!
- Down with Wayne!
Can I help you, pal?
I don't know what to say.
Do you want an autograph
or something?
No.
My name is Arthur.
Penny Fleck is my mother.
Jesus.
You're the guy that came
to my house yesterday?
Yes.
I'm sorry I just showed up.
Well, my mother
told me everything.
And I had to talk to you,
- you know?
- Look, pal, I'm not your father.
I mean, what's
wrong with you?
Look at us.
- I think you are.
- Well, that's impossible.
Because you were adopted and
I never slept with your mother.
What do you want
from me, money?
No. I don't want.
- I wasn't adopted.
- Jesus. She never told you?
Told me what?
Your mother adopted you while
she was working for us.
That's not true.
Why are you saying that?
Because she was arrested and
committed to Arkham State Hospital
..when you were just a little boy.
Why are you saying this?
I don't need you to tell me lies.
I know it seems strange.
I don't mean to make
you uncomfortable.
I don't why everyone is so rude,
and I don't why you are,
I don't want anything from you.
Maybe a little bit of warmth,
maybe a hug dad!
How much as a little bit
of fucking decency?
What is it with you people?!
Did you see the way
suffer my mother?
- She's crazy.
- She's-- huh-huh!
- You think this is funny?
- Yeah---huh-huh!
Dad, it's me!
Come on---huh--huh!
You touch my son again,
I'll fucking kill you!
Hello, Mr. Fleck.
This is detective Garrity.
We met the other night
at the Gotham General.
My partner and I had
a few more questions for you.
We stopped by your apartment today,
but you weren't at home.
Please, give me a call when
you've heard this message.
Again, this is detective Garrity.
My number is 212---99.
Uh, this message is
for Arthur Fleck.
My name is Shirley Woods,
I work on the Murray Franklin show.
I don't know
if you're aware,
but Murray played a clip of your
stand-up on the show recently
and we've gotten an amazing
response from our viewers.
And Mr. Murray asked me to
give you a call and see if you're---
Who is this?
Oh. Hi, this is Shirley Woods.
I'm the show-booker from
Live With Murray Franklin.
Is this Arthur?
Yes.
Hi, Arthur.
Well, and as I was saying,
we've gotten a lot of calls about
your clip, amazing responses.
And, Murray asked if I
would reach out to you
to see if you would
come on as his guest.
Murray wants me to come
on the Murray Franklin show?
Yeah. Isn't that great?
He'd love to talk to you,
maybe do some of your act.
Does that sound good to you?
Yeah, that's sounds great.
Can we set up
a date right now?
Are you available next Thursday?
Hey.
Wooh. Man.
Sorry about that, my man.
All our records that are 10 years
or older are stored in the basement
and you're talking about
something' 30 years ago, so.
Can I ask you a question?
Sure.
How does someone
wind up in here?
Have they all---
all the people committed crimes?
Oh, yeah. Some have.
Some are just crazy and pose a
danger to themselves or others.
Some just got
nowhere else to go.
Don't know what to do, you know?
- Yeah, I hear you, brother.
Sometimes, I don't
know what to do.
Last time I ended up taking
it out on some people.
I thought it was gonna bother me
but, it really hasn't.
What's that?
I fucked up.
I've done some bad shit.
Um...
You know what
I'm talking about.
It’s so hard just to try and be
happy all the time.
Hey, um, listen, man...
I'm just an
administrative assistant.
Like a clerk, you know.
All I do is file paperwork,
I don't know what to tell you,
but you should see somebody.
They have programs,
city services, stuff like that.
Oh, yeah.
They cut all those.
All right.
Here it is.
Fleck. Penny Fleck. I see.
Diagnosed by
Dr. Benjamin Stoner...
Oh, the patient suffers from
delusional psychosis
and narcissistic
personality disorder...hm.
Was found guilty of
endangering the welfare
of her own child--
What?
You said she's your mother?
I'm sorry,man. Like I said, I can't
release these records, you know,
without the proper forms.
I--I could get in trouble.
Look, if you wanna bring your mom in
here to sign, that would be much easier,
but, I can't-- I can't let this go
without a signature, okay?
I'm sorry.
No, man!
Come on, man! Give it to me!
Hey! Hey!
We went over this, Penny.
You adopted him.
We have all the
paperwork right here.
That's not true.
Thomas had them
all made up,
so it stayed our secret.
You also stood by
as one of your boyfriends
repeatedly abused
your adopted son
and battered you.
Penny,
your son was found
tied to a radiator
in your filthy apartment,
malnourished, with multiple
bruises across his body
and severe trauma to his head.
I never heard him crying.
He's always been such
a happy little boy.
Shh...it's time for bed.
Oh, my god!
What are you doing in here?
You're in the wrong apartment.
Your name is Arthur, right?
You live down the hall.
I really need you to leave.
My little girl is sleeping
in the other room.
Please.
I've had a bad day.
Can I call someone?
Is your mother home?
Hi, Penny.
Penny Fleck.
I always hated that name.
You know, you used to tell me
that my laugh
was a condition,
that there are
something wrong with me.
There isn't.
That’s the real me.
Ha--appy
"Happy".
Funny.
I haven't been happy
for one minute of my
entire fucking life.
You know what's funny?
You know what really
makes me laugh?
I used to think that
my life was a tragedy,
but now I realize
that's a fucking comedy.
A very fine actor.
He's got a new movie
called 'American Playboy',
opening this week across the country.
Will you please welcome
a good friend of the
show, Mr. Ethan Chase.
Good to see you, Ethan.
You looking great.
Thank you very much.
You look good yourself.
Ah, can't complain.
Hi, Murray,
Thank so much for having---
Hey, Murray.
Thank you so much for
having me on the show.
It's been a lifetime
dream of mine.
I'm nervous right now.
- What?
- I am.
Hey, Murray.
I've been a ---
That's---
I'm sorry, what's that?
Oh, that's really funny, Murray.
You know, I'm also a comedian.
Would you like to hear a joke?
Yeah?
All of you?
Okay.
Knock.
Knock- knock.
♪ - That's life ♪
♪ - (that's life) ♪
♪ that's what ♪
♪ all the people say ♪
♪ You're riding high in April ♪
♪ Shot down in May ♪
♪ But I know I'm gonna ♪
♪ change that tune ♪
♪ When I'm back on top, ♪
♪ back on top in June ♪
♪ - I said, that's life ♪
♪ - (that's life) ♪
♪ And as funny as it may seem ♪
♪ Some people get their kicks ♪
♪ Stompin' on a dream ♪
♪ But I don't let it, ♪
♪ let it get me down ♪
♪ 'Cause this fine old world ♪
♪ it keeps spinnin' around ♪
♪ I've been a puppet, a pauper, a pirate ♪
♪ A poet, a pawn and a king ♪
♪ I've been up and down ♪
♪ and over and out ♪
♪ And I know one thing ♪
♪ Each time I find myself ♪
♪ flat on my face ♪
♪ I pick myself up and get back in the race ♪
♪ - That's life ♪
♪ - (that's life) ♪
♪ I tell ya, I can't deny it ♪
♪ I thought of quitting, baby ♪
♪ But my heart just ain't gonna buy it ♪
♪ And if I didn't think ♪
♪ it was worth one single try ♪
Coming!
♪ I'd jump right on ♪
♪ a big bird and then I'd fly ♪
Hey, Arthur.
How's it going?
Oh, hi, guys.
Come on in.
Did you, uh,
get a new gig?
No.
Oh, you must be going down
to that rally at City Hall.
I hear It's gonna be nuts.
Is it today?
Yeah.
What's with the make-up, then?
My mom died.
I'm celebrating.
Right. Uh.. we heard. That's--
That's why we came by. Figured...
uh, you could use
some cheering up.
Oh, that's sweet.
But, no.
I feel good.
I stopped taking
my medication.
I feel lot better now.
Oh, okay.
Well, good for you.
So, hey, listen. Uh, I don't
know if you're heard, but..
the cops had been calling
around the shop
talking all the guys about
those subway murders.
They didn't talk to me.
That's because the suspect
was a regular sized person.
If it was a fucking midget
you'd be in jail right now.
Anyway, um...
Hoyt said that, um...
they talked to you and
now they're looking for me---
I just want to know
what you said.
Make sure our stories line up,
- seeing as, um--
- Yeah.
- you're my boy and, uh
- Yeah,
- it makes lot of sense,
- you know what I mean?
Thank you, Randall.
Thank you so much.
- I just wanna--
- Oh ,fuck!
Oh, god!
No!
What?
Why would you do that?
Do you watch Murray
Franklin show?
Yeah.
I'll be on it tonight.
It's fucking crazy 'innit?
Me on a telly.
What the fuck, Arthur?
What?
It's okay, Garry.
You can go.
I'm not gonna hurt you.
Don't look.
Just go.
Oh, fuck.
- H- Hey Arthur?
- Yeah?
Arthur, can you get.....the lock?
Oh!
Shit.
It's alright, Garry.
- Garry?
- Yeah?
You’re the only one that’s
ever been nice to me.
Get out of here.
Hey, Arthur!
We need to talk!
Hey, stop, Arthur!
Arthur!
- You fucking---
- Hey, out of the way!
Move!
Arthur!
- Hey!
Arthur, stop!
Go! Go!
Stand clear of
the closing doors.
Hold that train!
Hold it!
Open the fucking door!
Get out! Get out!
Next stop,--
- Hey, asshole!
- Better watch it!
Stand down! Now!
Police!
Stand down!
- Hey, what the fuck?
- Oh!
Stop fighting!
Police! Police!
Get down!
Get the fuck down!
Police, get down!
What the--?
Arthur!
Hey!
God, no!
Two officer on the train were violently
confronted by the crowd tonight
and they're in serious but stable
condition at Gotham Metropolitan.
We're going live now to
co-anchor Courtney Weathers
who's standing by outside
the Bedford park station
near where the
shooting took place.
Courtney, what's
the scene there?
- Murray!
- Hey, hey, hey!
- It's "Mr. Franklin!".
- Oh, come on, Gene.
That's all bullshit.
Thank you, Murray.
I feel like I know you.
I've been watching
you forever.
Thank you.
What's with the face?
That mean that you we're
part of the protest?
No. No.
No, I don't believe
in any of that.
I don't believe in anything.
I just thought it would
be good for my act.
For your act? Didn't you hear
what happened on the subway?
- Some clown got killed.
- He's aware of that, yeah.
No, I haven't heard.
- Yeah?
- You see ,this is what I’m telling you.
the audience is gonna go
crazy if you put this guy on.
Maybe-- maybe for a bit,
but not a whole segment.
Gene, It's gonna work.
It's gonna work.
We're gonna go with it.
Thank you, Murray.
Couple of rules though:
No cursing,
no off-color material,
- we do a clean show, okay?
You go on right after Dr. Sally.
- I love Dr. Sally.
- Good! Good, good.
- Well, someone will come
and get you, okay? - Okay.
Perfect.
- Good luck.
- Thanks, Murray.
Okay.
Hey, Murray...
one small thing.
- Yeah?
- When you bring me out
can you introduce
me as "Joker"?
What's wrong with
your real name?
That's what you
called me on the show.
A Joker.
Do you remember?
- Did I?
- Yeah, I don't know.
Well, if you say so, kid,
you know, joker it is.
- It's good.
- Thanks, Murray.
I would try it, you know, but I'm not
sure my wife would let me do it.
Maybe my next wife.
You gotta see our next
guest for yourself.
I'm pretty sure this
guy can use a doctor.
Oh, does he have
a sexual problem?
He looks like he's got
a lot of problems.
Alright, Let's show
that clip one last time.
I hated school as a kid.
But my mother
would always say,
"You should enjoy it.
One day you'll have
to work for a living."
"No I won't, Ma.
I'm gonna be a comedian!"
Okay,
you may have seen that
clip of our next guest.
Now, before he comes
out, I just want to say
that we're all heartbroken about
what's going on in the city tonight.
But, this is how he
wanted to come out.
And, honestly, I think
we could all use a good laugh.
So, please welcome "Joker".
Are you alright, doctor?
Well, that was...
quite an interest.
You okay?
Oh, yeah.
This is exactly
how I imagined it.
Well, that makes one of us.
So, can you tell
us about this look?
When we spoke earlier,
you mentioned
that this look is not a political
statement, is that right?
That's right, Murray.
I'm not political.
I'm just trying to
make people laugh.
And how's that
goin' for ya?
It's alright. It's alright.
So, I know you're a comedian.
Have you been working
on any new material?
You want to tell us a joke?
Yeah?
Okay.
He's got a book.
A book of jokes.
Take your time.
We go all night.
Okay. Okay.
Here's one.
Knock-knock.
And you had to look that up?
I wanted to get it right.
Knock-knock.
Who's there?
It's the Police, ma'am.
Your son has been hit
by a drunk driver.
He's dead.
Oh, no, no, no!
No, you cannot
joke about that.
Yeah, that's not funny, Arthur.
That's not the kind of humor
we do on this show.
Okay, I'm s--
Yeah, I'm sorry.
It's just, you know,
it's been a rough
few weeks, Murray,
ever since I
killed those three wall-street guys.
Okay. I'm waiting
for the punchline.
There is no punchline.
It's not a joke.
You're serious, aren't you?
You're telling us you killed those
three young men on the subway?
- M-hm.
- And why should we believe you?
I've got nothing left to lose.
Nothing can hurt me anymore.
My life is nothing but a comedy.
Let me get this straight, you think
that killing those guys is funny?
I do.
And I'm tired of
pretending it's not.
Comedy is subjective, Murray.
Isn't that what they say?
All of you,
the system that
knows so much,
you decide what's
right or wrong
the same way that you
decide what's funny...
or not.
Get him off!
Well, okay, I--I think
I might understand that you
did this to start a movement,
to become a symbol.
Come on, Murray,
do I look like the kind of a clown
that could start a movement?
I killed those guys
because they were awful.
Everybody's awful these days.
It's enough to
make anyone crazy.
Okay. So that's it, you're crazy.
That's your defense
for killing three
young men?
Nah.
They couldn't carry a tune
to save their lives.
Oh! Why is everybody
so upset about these guys?
If it was me dying on the side-walk,
you'd walk right over me.
I pass you everyday and you
don't notice me! but these guys,
what, because Thomas Wayne
went and cried about them on TV?
Well, you have a problem
with Thomas Wayne,too?
Yes, I do.
Have you seen what
it's like out there, Murray?
Do you ever actually
leave the studio?
Everybody just yells and
screams at each other.
Nobody's civil anymore!
Nobody thinks what
it's like to be the other guy.
You think men like Thomas Wayne
ever think what it's like
to be someone like me?
To be somebody but themselves?
They don't.
They think that we'll just
sit there and take it
like good little boys!
That we won't
werewolf and go wild.
You finished?
I mean, there is so much
self-pity, Arthur.
You sound like you're making
excuses for killing those young men.
Not everybody- and I'll tell you this-
not everyone is awful.
- But you're awful, Murray.
- Me?
I'm awful? Oh, yeah?
How am I awful?
Playing my video,
inviting me on the show---
You just wanted to
make fun of me.
You're just like the rest of 'em.
You don't know the first
thing about me, pal.
Look what happened because
of what you did, what it led to.
There are riots out there.
Two policemen are in critical
condition and you're laughing.
You're laughing.
Someone was killed today
because of what you did.
I know.
How about a another joke, Murray?
No, I think we got
enough of your jokes.
- What do you get..
- I don't think so.
..when you cross a mentally-ill
loner with a society
that abandons him and
treats him like trash?
Call the police, Gene.
- I'll tell you what you get.
- Call the police!
You get what you
fucking deserve!
Good night.
And always remember.
That's--
Breaking news.
Popular TV talk show host
Murray Franklin was
shot dead tonight on the live telecast
of his program by one of his guests.
--the man who was introduced by Franklin
as "Joker" is currently under arrest--
-- The police led the suspect
handcuffed out of the studio--
- ...when asking him what he did..
- ...merely just a punchline to a joke...
- Would you like another joke?
- I don't think so.
...with the society that abandons him
and treats him like trash.
If it was me dying on the side-walk,
you'd walk right over me!
To all of those who have been
ignored by the system--
--and as you can see,
Gotham is burning---
Stop laughing you freak.
This isn't funny.
We have the whole fucking city's
on fire because of what you did.
All units, fire reported.
North of ally.
I know.
Isn't it beautiful?
Let's go over there.
Hey, Wayne.
You get what you
fucking deserve.
No, pal!
Joker!
What's so funny?
I just think--
--just thinking of this joke.
You wanna tell it to me?
You wouldn't get it.
♪ --that's life. ♪
♪ (that's life) ♪
♪ and as funny as it may seem ♪
♪ Some people get their kicks ♪
♪ Stompin' on a dream ♪
♪ But I don't let it, ♪
♪ let it get me down ♪
♪ 'Cause this fine old world ♪
♪ it keeps spinnin' around ♪
♪ I've been a puppet, a pauper, a pirate ♪
♪ A poet, a pawn and a king ♪
♪ I've been up and
down and over and out ♪
♪ And I know one thing ♪
♪ Each time I find myself ♪
♪ laying flat on my face ♪
♪ I just pick myself up and ♪
♪ get back in the race ♪
♪ - That's life ♪
♪ - (that's life) ♪
♪ That's life and I tell ya, ♪
♪ I can't deny it ♪
♪ Many times I thought of cuttin' ♪
♪ out but my heart won't buy it ♪
♪ But if there's nothing ♪
♪ shakin' come here this July ♪
♪ I'm gonna roll myself up ♪
♪ in a big ball and die ♪